Jayanth Donekal SOFTWARE ENGINEER

https://github.com/JayDonekal LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayanth-donekal

8 Eglinton Ave East, Toronto, ON // Mobile: 647-575-4420 // jayanthdonekal@gmail.com



PROFILE

Proven experience in leading development team on large projects or programs interfacing with multiple applications and/or third parties. Development experience in Java Microservice and Spring Framework and Node Js. Experience with RESTful services, familiar with JEE and Skill for writing reusable Java libraries. Experience with OOP, Core Java, Java 8 programming and React.



EDUCATION

Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology, March 2021 Centennial College, Toronto, ON

Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Information Management, 2019
University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, UK | Merit Degree with Honours

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.) in Computer Science & Engineering, 2018 Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India

EXPERIENCE



Senior Programmer/Analyst | SickKids

Toronto, Canada | March 2023 - present

- ▶ Build, maintain and deploy full-stack web applications using Java, Node Js, and React; GitLab pipelines; and technical documentations.
- ▶ Create custom web pages with JSPX, JavaScript, and Kendo UI for data translation, along with Java Spring boot and MySQL for data management.
- ▶ Carryout design conceptualization using Figma and match front-end web styling to given specifications.
- Write SQL views and create embedded queries to retrieve data from various large hospital systems.
- ▶ Introduced CI/CD pipelines to deploy Dockerized applications into Azure cloud services.
- Design and test new features and review code written by peers.

Software Engineer | FutureVault Inc.

Toronto, Canada | May 2021 - March 2023

- Assist in developing a leading cloud-based document storage and management solution.
- ▶ Handling complete creation of microservices starting with the initial application creation, writing JAVA REST API's, construction of MongoDB databases, setting up communication between microservices with rest templates, integration into cloud services such as AWS, and deployments onto public load balancers.
- Understanding of Spring Securities, OIDC, OAuth 2.0 (Cognito) and SAML 2.0 protocols
- ► Containerization of microservices with Docker and orchestration using Kubernetes and AWS EKS technologies to achieve internal communication between applications.
- ▶ Setting system access control through IAM and RBAC services.
- ▶ Testing of services with Junit, Mockito, and postman.
- ▶ Documentations of APIs through Swagger and Spring REST Docs.
- ▶ Introduced Public APIs to assist developers with interfacing backend APIs directly.

- Write CI/CD pipelines to setup microservice applications on test, dev, and production cloud environments.
- Worked extensively with system integrations connecting multiple CRM applications to add singles sign-on authentication.

Junior Developer Intern | Taurus Hard Soft Solutions

Bangalore, India | Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

- ▶ Designing, programing, and launching a collaborative portal aimed at user data management for the Center for Human Genetics (CHG) India.
- Developed program with technologies Java, Hibernate, Bootstrap, and HTML JSP, within a Maven Environment
- Project estimations along with function point analysis and business workshops, use case testing,

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java Spring Boot
- ▶ Node Js, React, JavaScript and TypeScript
- ▶ Microservices, REST API'S, and RestTemplates
- ▶ Spring cloud config server and Parameter store integrations
- ▶ OAuth and Spring security with role-based access control
- SSL/TLS and certificate management for HTTPS
- ▶ CI/CD pipelines
- ▶ SSO and CRM (Salesforce) app integration
- Amazon web services and Azure cloud development
- Docker and Kubernetes
- ▶ NoSQL (MongoDB), MySQL, PL/SQL

Т